# **Angel Joaquin Berrio Luque**

angeljoaquin.berrioluque@outlook.com • linkedin.com/in/angelberrio Telf. +51 922535379 • Av. Paseo de la República 2199, Lima, Perú

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

I am a Systems Engineer, and I am part of the global IT Corporate Support team at Prosegur, with over six years of experience in information technology in the telecommunications sector. I specialize in diagnosing and resolving complex technical issues, focusing on the customer to provide exceptional support. I excel in generating value through the design and implementation of strategic projects, with skills in management and effective communication with stakeholders. I actively contribute to digital transformation and promote a culture of business innovation.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Senior IT Support Analyst**

Jan 2023 - Present

Cia de Seguridad Prosegur S.A • Remote Work, Lima, Perú

- Manage incidents and requests in the cash innovation systems received through the Remedy System (Helix Portal) globally, prioritizing according to knowledge and criticality using ITIL best practices.
- Coordinate with global development teams and local support to detect and report potential code errors through database analysis, application servers.
- · Generate reports upon Business request or other systems using PowerBI, DBeaver tools.
- Document and analyze the incidents and requests received in order to automate repetitive tasks that may affect the customer
- Coordinate with responsible parties for the integration of new corporate businesses.

### Vice Chief of IT Operation

Aug 2019 - Dec 2022

Viettel Perú S.A.C. • Presencial, Lima, Perú

- Deputy Head of the IT department whose mission is to supervise and control the operation of BSS (Business Support System) and OSS (Operation Support System) systems, actively participating in technical committees for new implementations and requirements requested by other areas.
- Participate in War Room sessions during incidents in production environments.
- Evaluate, monitor, and advise on IT applications to ensure they meet the necessary controls before their release to production.

Main Implementation Projects:

- ✓ Implementation of the "Banking" system enables physical and logical connection with financial entities through independent Webservices per entity. It enables millions of Bitel users to recharge and pay mobile and internet services through various financial channels such as banks, municipal savings banks, and virtual points.
- ✓ The reconciliation system automates the commission payment process to partner entities. It utilizes stored procedures and a dashboard to generate decision-making indicators. The implementation significantly reduced reconciliation times and allowed for more effective commercial strategies with partners showing better commission indicators.
- ✓ In charge of implementing the second and third phases of the **Renteseg project**, integrating the BITEL and OSIPTEL platforms through automated exchange of encrypted files. Driven by the technical and legal team of OSIPTEL, the implementation facilitated sharing BITEL's Subscriber Registration Database and the database of stolen, blocked, and released devices in an automated manner.
- ✓ Implementation of the **ServiceDesk & OpManager system** for incident management and network monitoring in corporate clients in the private and public sectors. Collaborative work with the MangaEngine partner, based on analysis of client technical terms and joint plan design. These implementations strengthened Bitel's service reputation, meeting reference terms and attracting significant projects in the public sector.

## **Application Support Analyst**

Apr 2018 - Jul 2019

Viettel Perú S.A.C. • Presencial, Lima, Perú

- Application analyst, monitoring, and control of Linux Operating Systems in their various distributions and Windows Server 2012 R2, operation of Oracle and MySQL relational databases and Non-Relational MongoDB, maintenance and updates of Apache Web services, Java, creation of scripts for automation.
- Implementation of new modules for high availability, Load Balance configuration.

- Design and implementation of Database Structure and Data Dictionary, creation of Stored Procedures and packages, triggers, sequences.
- Management of data logs. Creation of files, folders, and batch files.
- Documentation of implementations, Change Requests, and Updates management.

**Team Leader NOC IT** Sep 2017 - Mar 2018

Viettel Perú S.A.C. • Presencial, Lima, Perú

- Responsible for the operation of IT systems, ensuring business continuity through the management and implementation of alarms, high availability of systems, and databases.
- Provide training and coaching to team members.
- Clearly communicate instructions to team members.
- Generate reports to inform the company about team progress and KPIs.

Jul 2016 - Ago 2017 **NOC IT Engineer** 

Viettel Perú S.A.C. • Presencial, Lima, Perú

- Responsible for the detection, tracking, and resolution of alarms on IT devices including servers (Linux, Windows Server), applications (Java, JBoss, .NET), and databases (Oracle DB, MongoDB, MySQL).
- Analyze the root cause of alarms for short-term solutions through log reviews, and escalate the issue to higher levels for long-term resolution.
- Provide support to all areas of the company related to IT requests/problems through the ManageEngine ServiceDesk ticketing tool.
- Generate reports for management on server performance, database performance, user equipment access control, and national-level security camera operations.

#### **EDUCATION**

Systems Engineer, Degree Aug 2010 - Dec 2022

Universidad Privada César Vallejo • Los Olivos, Perú

Computer applications specialist, Diploma Jul 2015 - Dec 2016

Centro de Informática y Sistemas UCV • Los Olivos, Perú

**SKILLS/ABILITIES** 

Innovation and creativity Linux/Windows **Unix Scripting** 

Problem-solving profile Server **Network Protocols** 

Analytical ability Agile SAFe Java Docker

PL/SQL Oracle/SQL Server

#### PROFESSIONAL CREDENTIALS

- Ordinary member of The College of Engineers in Perú (CIP 307126)
- ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management (ITIL 4)
- Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate (SFPC)
- Institute BRITANICO: English Intermediate Level

#### AWARDS AND HONOURS

**Best Employee** 

Badge of honour received recognizing the effort and contribution made during 2019 in the IT Department of Viettel Perú SAC Company.

**Certificate of Completion** 2018

A training Course on: Knowledge and Profession Training for IT Systems Operation. Held on 01St October to 20 December 2018, Hanoi, Vietnam.

**Certificate of Completion** 2019

A training course of: Oracle Database, SQL and PL/SQL Fundamentals.